Oluyemi Adetule

Facilities Engineer

Wilmington, DE - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Oluyemi-Adetule/b913b3f734794a96

A maintenance, facilities, reliability and plant engineer bringing to the table a wealth of experience in technology, entrepreneurship and management - with high aptitude for achieving goals, leading and managing multicultural teams across emerging and developed markets. Other strengths include strong oral and written communication skills, problem-solving, and ability to simplify complex subjects. Specialties include consulting, process engineering, project engineering, project management, production system, operational excellence, energy management, capability building and business development.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Facilities Engineer

The Ritz-Carlton - White Plains, NY - July 2013 to November 2015

- Maintain the entire hotel facility, including the physical building structure, all mechanical equipment-chillers, boilers, water softeners, and refrigeration equipment; electrical, HVAC systems, and related equipment in accordance with energy conservation and preventative maintenance programs. Ensure the upkeep of guest areas to maintain an attractive hotel.
- Conduct walk-throughs and visually assess the safe and efficient maintenance and operation of the physical structure(s) of the hotel, all mechanical, electrical, HVAC systems and any other related equipment.
- Maintain effective energy management and preventive maintenance programs and conducted special training for other operating departments on the safe and efficient use of equipment and energy in the hotel.
- Perform fire prevention, environmental health and safety on all engineering and building systems. Attended all meetings regarding hotel operations: department, fire, safety, health, quality improvement.
- Inform the supervisor on a regular basis regarding the specific and overall condition of the building structure(s), related systems, and equipment offering prudent, cost effective proposals for maintaining these systems. Accessed and input information into a computer and generate reports.
- Perform necessary repairs and maintenance throughout the hotel. Assigned department employees to make electrical, carpentry, plumbing, plastering, painting, locksmith and other mechanical installations and repairs.
- · Verify completion of all repairs, replacement, and renovation projects to offices and employee work areas.
- Prepare technical data, bidding, project work, alterations and repairs for properties.
- Manage water treatment programs.

Senior Facilities Engineer

Afren Energy - NG - May 2007 to July 2012

- Maintained and repaired physical plant and all of its features, including: day-to-day system operation and maintenance routines such as preventive maintenance, minor and major repairs and improvements on boilers, chillers, pumps and other appliances.
- Coordinated maintenance scheduling to optimize equipment performance by supervising technicians as regards their daily schedule.
- Directed production schedule with planning team by instructing technicians on what to do in order to satisfy customers demand.
- Managed team schedules and technician staffing levels to ensure proper utilization of team.

- Provided timely and competent process engineering for plant operations to address safety, integrity and reliability related problems and proposes / implements system upgrades.
- Performed process optimization studies to identify, evaluate capital and operating cost savings, product configuration alternatives and safety facilities requirements.

Facilities Engineer

3) Niger Delta Exploration and Production (NDEP) - NG - March 2003 to May 2007

Ensured adequate spare parts inventory, optimizes & coordinates scheduling of preventative, predictive & corrective maintenance to improve equipment reliability.

- Provided shop floor day-to-day equipment / instrumentation / robotic & utilities engineering support to manufacturing operations.
- Developed maintenance programs for preventive maintenance, scheduling of equipment and manpower, requirements for new equipment, and reviewing technical aspects of budgets and accountability.
- Maintained a high level of technical knowledge and may coordinate safety, current Good Manufacturing Practices, and environmental compliance programs.
- Actively supported productivity improvement program and resolution of deviation events.
- Participated in root cause investigations, evaluates, develops and improves business processes and develops technical rationale for system improvements.
- Verified completion of all routine maintenance on public spaces, meeting rooms, ballrooms, outlets, back of the house spaces, and grounds.

EDUCATION

M.Eng. in Chemical Engineering

Cornell University May 2013

Chemical

American Institute of Chemical Engineers and American Chemical Society workshops 2002 to 2003

B.Tech. in Chemical Engineering

Ladoke Akintola University March 2001

SKILLS

Microsoft Office Suite, Microsoft Office Suite (10+ years)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

SKILLS

Microsoft Office Products: Excel, Power Point, Word, Visio, MS Project and SharePoint